Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.7
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-pro",
"thinking_budget": 32768,
"max_subtitle_chars": 50,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180,
"start_offset_min": 0
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING PRECISION (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry are meticulously accurate.** Both must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and exact conclusion* of the spoken words (including any held notes or extended sounds) or the appearance/disappearance of on-screen text for that specific segment.
*   **Subtitle durations must be short, typically a few seconds.** Long durations (e.g., over 15 seconds) are incorrect and indicate a timing error.
*   **STRICT CHRONOLOGICAL ORDER (CRITICAL):**
*   **Every subtitle entry MUST be in strict chronological order.** The `start` time of any subtitle entry MUST be greater than or equal to the `end` time of the immediately preceding subtitle entry.
*   **Crucially, subtitle segments MUST NOT overlap.** The `start` time of a new segment must be greater than or equal to the `end` time of the previous segment.
*   **Any deviation from strict chronological order or overlapping segments will result in immediate rejection and re-processing of the entire segment.** This is a non-negotiable requirement.
*   Timestamps must always be in `MM:SS` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **COMPREHENSIVE CONTEXTUAL UNDERSTANDING:**
*   **Watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative. This holistic understanding is crucial for accurate transcriptions and translations.
*   **Always combine logical sentences or phrases split across multiple subtitle entries** to understand the full, complete meaning before translating. Ensure each translated entry is a coherent part of the overarching sentence.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals, surrounding dialogue, speaker intent, tone) to infer the most probable dialogue.
*   **DO NOT HALLUCINATE:** Only transcribe and translate content that is actually present in the video (spoken or on-screen). Do not invent dialogue or text.
*   **Include relevant on-screen text:** If there is text displayed on screen that is relevant to the video's content, transcribe and translate it as well, ensuring its timing aligns with its appearance on screen.
*   **Example of Holistic Translation:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **TRANSLATION ACCURACY & NUANCE:**
*   **Prioritize natural-sounding translations:** Translations should read as if originally written in the target language, avoiding overly literal or awkward phrasing.
*   **Maintain cultural appropriateness:** Adapt idioms, cultural references, and nuances to resonate with the target audience while preserving the original meaning.
*   **Ensure consistency:** Use consistent terminology and phrasing for recurring concepts or names throughout the entire transcription/translation.
4.  **DUAL LANGUAGE PROVISION:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue and relevant on-screen text.
5.  **READABILITY & FORMATTING:**
*   Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen. Aim for natural breaks that preserve meaning.
*   Each subtitle entry (English and Japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters.
*   Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
6.  **REVIEW AND REFINE:**
*   Before finalizing, review all generated subtitles to ensure they meet all the above requirements, especially timing precision, chronological order, and translation accuracy.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
ありがとう 君がいてくれて
Thank you. I'm so glad you're here.
本当よかったよ
I'm really so glad.
どんな時だっていつも
No matter when, always...
笑っていられる
I can keep on smiling.
例えば離れていても
Even if we are apart,
何年たっても
no matter how many years pass,
ずっと変わらないでしょ
we will never change, right?
私たち Best Friend
We're best friends.
好きだよ、
I love you.
大好きだよ
I love you so much.
こんな遅い時間にゴメンね
Sorry for contacting you this late.
一人じゃせっぱつまってきたの
I was getting overwhelmed on my own.
君の声少し聞けたら がんばれる
If I just hear your voice, I can keep going.
なんでも打ち明けられるママにも
I can confide everything,
言えないことも全部
even the things I can't tell my mum.
誰よりもわかってくれる
You understand me more than anyone.
嬉しいときには 自分の事みたいに
When I'm happy, it's like it's your own
喜んでくれて
happiness, and you celebrate with me.
ダメな時はちゃんとしかって
When I'm wrong, you properly scold me.
くれる存在
That's the kind of person you are.
ありがとう君がいてくれて
Thank you, I'm so glad you're here.
本当よかったよ
I'm really so glad.
どんな時だっても
No matter when,
笑っていられる
I can keep on smiling.
例えば離れていても
Even if we are apart,
何年たっても
no matter how many years pass,
ずっと変わらないでしょ
we will never change, right?
私たち Best Friend
We're best friends.
好きだよ、
I love you.
大好きだよ
I love you so much.
強がってもすぐにバレてる
You see right through me when I act tough.
へこんでる時は真っ先にメール
When I'm down, you're the first to text.
くれる優しさにもう何度も救われて
Your kindness has saved me so many times.
泣きたい時は思いっきり泣けばいい
When you want to cry, just cry your heart out.
側にいるからって
'Cause I'll be right here by your side.
誰よりも強い味方
My strongest ally, more than anyone.
A stronger ally than anyone else
そんな君に私は
For a friend like you,
何かしてあげられてるかな？
I wonder if I'm doing enough?
何かあったらすぐに
If anything ever happens,
飛んでくから、絶対
I'll come running, I promise
ありがとう君がいてくれて
Thank you for being here
本当よかったよ
I'm really so glad
どんな時だっていつも
No matter when, always
笑っていられる
I can be smiling
例えば離れていても
Even if we're apart
何年たっても
even if years pass
ずっと変わらないでしょ
We'll never change, right?
私たち Best Friend
We're Best Friends
好きだよ、
I love you,
大好きだよ
I love you so much
どんな時でも
No matter what,
祈ってるよ
I'm always praying for you
世界で一番に
I want you to be the happiest
幸せになってほしい
person in the world
ありがとう
Thank you
君がいてくれて
for being here
本当よかったよ
I'm really so glad
どんな時だっていつも
No matter when, always
笑っていられる
I can be smiling
例えば離れていても
Even if we're apart
何年たっても
even if years pass
ずっと変わらないでしょ
We'll never change, right?
私たち Best Friend
We're Best Friends
好きだよ、
I love you,
大好きだよ
I love you so much